Guide to the Administrative Papers of President John Crittenden Sawhill 1974-1981 (Bulk 1975-1979) RG.3.0.8
New York University Archives
- Series VI: Governance
  - President's Office; Christmas Party for Officers and Staff, Dec 1973-Dec 1979 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - President's Office; Miscellaneous, Oct 1973-Oct 1979 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - President's Office; Sample Letters, Oct 1962-May 1978 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - President's Reports; Distribution and Correspondence, Feb 1977-Mar 1980 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - President's Reports; Draft Material, Aug 1976-Aug 1979 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - President's Reports; to University Senate, Sep 1979 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - President's Trip; Sawhill to Israel, Mar 1977-Nov 1977 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - President's Trip; Bennett to Palm Beach, Feb 1980-Mar 1980 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - University, Miscellaneous, Aug 1975-Aug 1979 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - University, Senate, Jun 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - University, Senate, Oct 1976-Jun 1977 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - University, Senate, Sep 1977-May 1978 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - University, Senate, Oct 1978-Sep 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - University, Senate; Committees, Oct 1975-Apr 1976 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - University, Senate; Committees, Oct 1976-Jun 1977 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - University, Senate; Committees, Oct 1977-May 1979 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Budget Policies, Oct 1975-Sep 1976 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Educational Policies, Oct 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Financial Affairs, Dec 1976-May 1980 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Heath Service Subcommittee, Mar 1976 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Organization and Governance, May 1975-Oct 1976 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - University, Senate; Committees; Public Affairs, Apr 1977 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - University, Senate; Student Senators, May 1976-Feb 1980 (Box 34, Folder 19)
- Series VII: Government Relations
  This single Hollinger box, 1.25 linear feet, contains the limited amount of materials retained by the Sawhill office relating to the University's transactions with federal, state and local entities. Much of it is routine. Matters of interest may be found mainly among the Arnold Goren memoranda, Box 35, folder 15, Box 36, folder 2, Box 37, folders 6-13. Goren had represented the University in New York City and Albany on political matters dealing with higher education and specifically NYU prior to Sawhill's arrival at NYU; Sawhill continued this appointment, moving him into that role in the federal arena as well soon after the President's arrival, Box 35, folder 12, Goren to Sawhill 12/30/75.
  Box 35 contains a mixed assortment of items. Folder 4 contains an Op-ed piece 2/16/77 authored by John C. and Isabel V. Sawhill concerning the federal "marriage tax," also referenced in Series IX, and which was widely distributed. Folder 17 offers Carol Bellamy on (NY) City and State Budgets 3/24/79, see particularly p. 5, while Box 36, folder 11 contains a full copy of the 9/1/75 Report of the Regents Advisory Commission on the Financial Problems of Postsecondary Institutions. A brief summary of the state's role in addressing NYU's financial difficulties leading to the sale of the University Heights Campus in 1972 is found on pp. 167-169.
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Energy, Nov 1975-Dec 1978 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Health, Education, and Welfare, Mar 1975-Aug 1975 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Health, Education, and Welfare, Jan 1976-Sep 1980 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Miscellaneous, Dec 1974-Oct 1979 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; National Endowment for the Humanities, Jan 1976-Jan 1980 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; National Science Foundation, May 1975-Jan 1979 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Legislation; Miscellaneous, May 1975-Oct 1975 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Legislation; Miscellaneous, Jan 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Legislation; Miscellaneous, Jan 1977-Mar 1977 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies; Legislation; Miscellaneous, Apr 1977-Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Federal Office, Oct 1975-Jul 1979 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Federal Relations, May 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Federal Relations, Sep 1976-Mar 1980 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Government Relations, Jul 1975-Oct 1980 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - New York City; City, May 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - New York City; City, Sep 1976-Aug 1978 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - New York City; City, Sep 1978-Jun 1980 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - New York City; City; Miscellaneous, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - New York City; City University of New York, Jun 1974-Apr 1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - New York City; City University of New York, May 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - New York City; City University of New York, Jun 1977-Feb 1979 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - New York City; City University of New York; Professional Staff Congress Report, Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - New York State; Education Department, Aug 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - New York State; Education Department, Oct 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - New York State; Education Department, Sep 1977-Jun 1980 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - New York State; Education Department; Board of Regents, Jul 1975-May 1980 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - New York State; Education Department; Bundy Legislation/Aid, Jan 1976-Jul 1976 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - New York State; Education Department; Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education, Apr 1975-Jul 1975 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - New York State; Education Department; Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education, Sep 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - New York State; Education Department; Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education, Feb 1976-Jun 1976 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - New York State; Education Department; Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education, Oct 1976-Nov 1979 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - New York State; Education Department; Correspondence (Program Registration Approvals), Dec 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - New York State; Education Department; Doctoral Project (including D.A.), Jun 1975-Aug 1980 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - New York State; Education Department; Legislation/Aid, Aug 1977-May 1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - New York State; Education Department; Non-NYU Program Review, Dec 1975-Nov 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - New York State; Education Department; NYU Trustee/Albany Correspondence (Bundy Legislation/Aid), Apr 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - New York State; Government Relations; VP A. Goren Memoranda, Apr 1975-Apr 1978 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - New York State; Government Relations; VP A. Goren Memoranda, May 1978-Jan 1981 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - New York State; Legislation; Correspondence, May 1975-Jul 1975 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - New York State; Legislation; Correspondence, Sep 1975-Mar 1976 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - New York State; Legislation; Correspondence, Apr 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - New York State; Legislation; Correspondence, Sep 1977-Nov 1979 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - New York State; Office of the Governor, Oct 1976-Mar 1980 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - New York State; Regents Regional Coordinating Council for Post Secondary Education in New York City, Jun 1975-Jun 1976 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - New York State; State University of New York (SUNY), Aug 1975-Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Other States, Nov 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Series VIII: Personnel
  This series is contained in one Hollinger box, .833 linear feet. About one-third of its content is taken up with Sawhill correspondence with university faculty and staff, Box 38, folder 4-16. In folder 4, Sawhill comments on the state of the University to the University's former director of public relations 8/22/77. A second sequence, in Box 39, is concerned with officers' positions, folders 4-12. Limited amounts of material relating to benefits, employment, health services, retirement, salary administration, tenure and union activities constitute most of the remainder of this series. Some differences between faculty and Sawhill on benefit matters appear in Box 38, folder 3, while in Box 39 some University response to the faculty organizing drive appears in folders 20-21.
  - Benefits; Death Benefits, Jun 1976-May 1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Benefits; Faculty/Staff, Jan 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Benefits; Faculty/Staff, Oct 1976-Jun 1980 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence; (A-B), Nov 1975-May 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence; (C), Sep 1975-Oct 1980 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; (D-E), Dec 1975-Apr 1980 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence; (F), Nov 1975-May 1980 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence; (G), Dec 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence; (H), Sep 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence; (I-K), Jan 1976-Apr 1980 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence; (L), Jan 1976-May 1980 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence; (M), Apr 1975-Sep 1980 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence; (N-O), Mar 1976-May 1980 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence; (P-R), Sep 1975-Jan 1980 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence; (S), Apr 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; (T-Z), Oct 1975-May 1980 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Employment, Nov 1975-Oct 1980 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Employment; Affirmative Action, Jun 1975-Nov 1980 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence; Full Acccessibility, Sep 1975-Apr 1978 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Activities, Feb 1976-Oct 1980 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Handbook; Administrative and Professional (Staff); Policies and Benefits, Oct 1978 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Handbook; Faculty, Mar 1977-May 1977 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Handbook; Office and Technical Staff, Jun 1976 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Health Services, Aug 1975-Mar 1977 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, Aug 1975-Apr 1980 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Officers; Academic Planning and Services/Academic Affairs, Sep 1975-May 1980 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Officers; Administrative Services/Administration, Jun 1975-1978 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Officers; External Affairs, Sep 1975-Sep 1978 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Officers; Finance, Sep 1975-Aug 1979 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Officers; Institutional Faculties, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Officers; Legal Counsel and Secretary, Sep 1975-Dec 1980 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Officers; Public Affairs, May 1979-Jan 1980 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Officers; Student Affairs, Sep 1975-Apr 1980 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Officers Group; CVs and Resumes, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Retirement, Jan 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Retirement, Sep 1976-May 1978 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Retirement, Feb 1979-Aug 1980 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Salary Administration, Sep 1975-May 1976 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Salary Administration, Aug 1976-Feb 1980 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Tenure, Dec 1975-Apr 1979 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Union Activities, Sep 1975-Nov 1980 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Union Activities; Faculty, Jun 1975-Jan 1976 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Union Activities; Faculty, Feb 1976-Mar 1976 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Union Activities; Staff, Aug 1975-Oct 1980 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Public Relations, Aug 1975-Aug 1977 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Public Relations, Oct 1977-Jan 1978 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Public Relations, Jan 1978-Jul 1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Public Relations, Oct 1978-Aug 1979 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Public Relations, Sep 1979-Jun 1980 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Appointments of Interest (Sawhill), Sep 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Appointments of Interest (Sawhill), Jan 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Appointments of Interest (Sawhill), Jan 1977-Jun 1978 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Community Relations, Jan 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Community Relations, Oct 1976-Oct 1977 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Community Relations, Jan 1978-Feb 1979 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Community Relations, Mar 1979-Aug 1980 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Community Relations; Washington Square, Jun 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Community Relations; Washington Square, Jan 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Community Relations; Washington Square, Sep 1977-May 1980 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Condolences, Sep 1975-Aug 1978 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Condolences, Sep 1978-Nov 1980 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Congratulations, Apr 1975-Jun 1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Congratulations; 1975 (A-G), undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Congratulations; 1975 (H-L), undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Congratulations; 1975 (M-P), undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Congratulations; 1975 (S-Z), undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Congratulations; 1979 (Sawhill), Aug 1979-Sep 1979 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Congratulations; 1979 (Sawhill), Oct 1979 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Congratulations; 1979 (Bennett), Oct 1979-Aug 1980 (Box 41, Folder 13)
- Series IX: Public Relations
  This series is the largest in the Sawhill collection, suggesting the area of most interest to this presidency. It comprises 21 Hollinger boxes for a total of 9.165 linear feet. As in Series II, it contains both NYU and non-NYU related material, sometimes in tandem as in the course he taught for several semesters at GBA, listed as "Ethical Choices in Developing Energy Policy," Box 44, folders 9-13. Particulars of his views on NYU and non-NYU matters can be found in the dozens of texts of lectures, speeches, interviews, etc., which have been retained. The series' main groupings are: Intellectual Life in New York, Invitations, Public Occasions and Public Presentations. Also located in this series are his general and energy-related correspondence sequences, as noted previously.
  The series opens at Box 40, with a mixed grouping of public relations files. Sawhill can be seen reaching out into the local community in various ways in folders 1-2. A proposal addressing NYU's 150th Anniversary celebration can be found in folder 4, Levine to Sawhill. Acting President Ivan Loveridge Bennett Jr. takes on his new post, folder 5. A briefing piece prepared for the incoming Sawhill on community relations is in folder 9, Burneson to Sawhill, 8/1/75, along with a draft on dealing with the University's "neighbors," Maggin to Blumenfeld 6/4/76. NYU withdraws from the Washington Square Art Show in Box 41, folder 2, Patterson to Pagella 7/6/77, while folder 3 offers insight into the kinds of involvement with Washington Square Park NYU experienced.
  Box 42 contains the energy-related correspondence, assembled alphabetically. Folder 5 includes a Sawhill quotation covering an announcement of the publication of a group of energy-related dissertations, Garland Publishing, Inc, 1/79. Folder 23 sketches Sawhill's work as energy advisor to the Sargent Shriver for President campaign. Folder 27 offers a news note on a Sawhill proposed energy plan, Energy Users Report, Number 290, 3/1/79. Folder 28 is the first of three containing correspondence associated with the preparation of the report for the Trilateral Commission; folders 1-2 in Box 43 complete the sequence. Folder 2 contains a copy of a briefing paper on "Energy Conservation, Pricing, and Alternatives" presented by Sawhill to a New York business audience hosted by David Rockefeller, North American Chairman of the Trilateral Commission 1/8/79. General correspondence occupies the balance of Box 43, and continues into Box 44. The courses taught sequence follows, in turn succeeded by Intellectual Life in New York matters, filling much of Box 45. Invitations from University and external hosts appear next, extending through Box 46 and much of Box 47.
  Public Occasions incorporates several subsets, opening with a few folders devoted to Commencement matters; Box 47, folder 13 is the source of the highlight about the University's use of Washington Square Park, Sawhill to Lewis Rudin 3/12/76, and also contains a copy of Sawhill's remarks at his "first Commencement as President of NYU…" 6/3/76. Among the largest of the subsets, Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, fills much of Box 48 through Box 51, folder 8. Box 49, folder 1 offers a copy of Sawhill's remarks before a Real Estate Institute Dinner in which he discusses developments at NYU over the last year 3/24/77. A dinner for banking and securities industry executives to exchange views with Sawhill was hosted by NYU Trustee Lewis Preston 5/8/79, Box 50, folder 2, and Sawhill hosted a dinner for George H.W. Bush 3/14/79, Box 51, folder 4.
  The sequence titled Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks succeeds Public Occasions. This opens with the pre-NYU grouping mentioned in Scope and Content, Box 51, folder 9 through Box 52, folder 5. The next section is subtitled NYU, NYC, Education, and continues through Box 56, folder 7. Box 56, folder 8 picks up with the subtitle Energy, Economy, etc., through Box 59, folder 6. Among these voluminous files, Box 53 contains an attack on Sawhill's priorities for NYU 12/1/75. the Village Voice, folder 3, "The case for the large private university," an interview with Sawhill 2/9/76, folder 4, and Sawhill on leadership as a participant in a TIME Magazine-sponsored conference, TIME 11/8/76, folder 5. The New York Times Magazine of 4/30/78 published a major article by Times education editor Edward B. Fiske on NYU, crediting Sawhill with the "Miracle on Washington Square," Box 55, folder 3. The following year CHANGE Magazine also published a major, though less enthusiastic article authored by free-lance writer Ron Chernow, "John Sawhill: Academe's Crisis Manager," May-June 1979, Box 56, folder 4.
  In the Energy, Economy subset Sawhill testifies before the Maryland Public Service Commission on behalf of the Potomac Electric Power Company in a rate case, June (?) '76, Box 57, folder 5, the Durham (N.C) Morning Herald editorializes that "…(while) Mr. Sawhill continues to speak out on the need for serious conservation. It's a pity his words don't get more attention from government officials…" 1/2/77, Box 58, folder 1. Sawhill takes notes at the Seven Springs Center Symposium on "The Governance of Energy: The Proper Role of Industry and Government," 2/10-12/77 and, as noted in Series VII, publishes an Op-ed piece with wife Isabel V. Sawhill, "This article really is about income tax," both in Box 58, folder 2.
  In Box 60, miscellaneous correspondence concerned with Public Presentations occupies folders 1-10. Folder 10 contains Sawhill's "going on leave' letter, while folders 11-13 deal with Speakers Bureau matters; a Sawhill biographical brochure with suggested lecture topics appears in folder 12. The balance of this series, Box 61, opens with Publications, folders 1-7, and closes with a variety of routine materials, folders 10-13. Folder 1 includes a copy which appeared in the 5/7/78 Kansas City Star of the syndicated New York Times article by Edward B. Fiske referred to above. An NYU profile and listing of University Centennial memorabilia are found in folder 9.
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (A), undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (B), undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (C), undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (Clippings), undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (D), undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (E), undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (F), undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (FEA, re: resignation), undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (G), undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (H), undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (I), undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (INFORM), undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (J), undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (K), undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (L), undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (M), undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (N), undated (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (National Academy of Public Administration), undated (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (O), undated (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (P), undated (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (R), undated (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (S), undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (Shriver for President), undated (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (T), undated (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (U-V), undated (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (W), undated (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence; Energy Related; (X-Z), undated (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence; re: Energy Report; (Trilateral Commission), Feb 1974-Dec 1977 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence; re: Energy Report; (Trilateral Commission), Jan 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence; re: Energy Report; (Trilateral Commission), Sep 1978-Oct 1979 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence; General; (A), undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence; General; (B), undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence; General; (C), undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; General; (California, University of, Berkeley, Los Alamos), undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence; General; (D), undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence; General; (E), undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence; General; (F), undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence; General; (G), undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence; General; (H), undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence; General; (I), undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence; General; (J), undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence; General; (K), undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence; General; (L), undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; General; (M), undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence; General; (N), undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence; General; (O), undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence; General; (P), undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence; General; (R), undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence; General; (S), undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; General; (T), undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence; General; (U-V), undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence; General; (W-Y), undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Courses Taught; Correspondence, May 1977-Feb 1979 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Courses Taught; Sp 77, Fa 77, Sp 78, Fa 78; Description and Reading Lists, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Courses Taught; Fa 77, Sp 78, Fa 78; Final Exams, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Courses Taught; Sp 78, Fa 78; Lecture Notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Courses Taught; Planning, Feb 1977-Apr 1979 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Conference; Papers and Participants, Dec 1976 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Dinners, May 1977-Jun 1978 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Invitations and Follow-up, Feb 1977-Apr 1977 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Invitations and Follow-up, May 1977-Jun 1977 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Invitations and Follow-up, Jul 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Invitations and Follow-up, Sep 1977-Oct 1977 (Box 44, Folder 19)